nwod custom were race

were squid


genesis
biological mutation to expand their territory onto the land

age
?
certain reccounts from japan suggest they have been around for centuries but only recently have they been known elsewhere in the world

reproduction type: bloodline
must mate with each other or humans

human form: as normal

hybrid form: cthulian horror
size +2
strength+4
dexterity+1
stamina+1
perception+2 
armor+1

physical description:
skin runs pale green, eyes swell in size and slide apart, fingers elongate to several feet in length and grow rubbery, the upper lip bounces and stretches into tentical shaped protusions, the lower lip retracts entirely, exposing the jaw which changes shape into a beak, hair twines together to former pseudo tenticles, feet gain suction cups and take the shape of tenticles, nose splits into 2 "fins" and slide up to temples


animal form: giant squid
lethal damage from beak
size+5
strength+4
dexterity-2
stamina+1
perception+3


auspices: 

kraken
taking after the mythical squids who would grapple ships, the kraken can grapple an enemy with each of its 10 tenticals while in animal or hybrid form, additionally they can maintain existing grapples (hold/damage) as a reflexive action

observer
squids have eyes larger than any other creature on earth, observers take advantage of this and have honed their abilities of perception, as a result they add their primal urge to to all vision based rolls, including but not limited to seeing thru illusions, invisibility, and mundane deception

regenerator
squid regrow their tenticals and other parts very quickly, regenerators are called such because even among squid they are fast healers, they may regenerate a lethal health box in place of the normal bashing health box each turn

cthulian 
cthulian's believe the hybrid form is representaive of the old one cthulu and that this is responsible for the powers they aquire while in hybrid form, whether this is true or not is debatable but its as good an explanation as any as to why they suddenly manafest magic while in hybrid form, cthulians can learn and use mage rotes while in hybrid form, using primal urge in place of gnossis when applicable, their magic is always considered sympathetic casting(using essence in place of mana), cthulians start with 3 rotes in place of choosing aspects, new rotes cost 5 exp per dot and, for the purpose of meeting the prerequisites of the rote, treat the related spheres as 1 less than their primal urge(they do not however actually have spheres). as a side note, they also know "squidular mathematics" and can solve any math problem almost instantly since according to them "the process is the same reguardless of the problem"

marianas
squid have been to the deeper parts of the ocean, and one does not survive there unless you can hide from predators, marianas gain their primal urge rating as a bonus to stealth, they are also able to shoot ink at someone as an instant action, making a ranged attack (dex+ballistics), doing so inflicts the target with blindness for one round, which is typically used to escape


rage type: madness
derrangement from rage: obsessive compulsive

inborn aspects
regeneration 
silver weakness
ressurection

