pathfinder cactuar and tonberry races
v1.0.2.20.8
change log
added rancor usage limits
moved some tonberry feats to racial prestige
added safety clarifying text at the end of suppressed hatred
added added new sorceror bloodlines

cactuar
standard(dex+2 int-2 chr+2)(0)
small(0)
fast(1)
plant(10)
prickly(1)
grappling a cactuar inccurs 1d4 damage
needle shot(3)
as a standard action the cactuar may make a ranged touch attack that does 1 damage that ignores damage reduction. if you gain abilities that increase the number of needles fired, all needles go off 1 attack roll

total: 15

racial traits

dessert runner
cactuar are at home in the dessert where they run wild, cactuar with this trait gain +5 ft move in sand

stick in the sun
cactuars can stay extremely still and pretend to be an actual cactus, you gain a +2 bonus to stealth and disguise when in the dessert


racial feats

needle barrage
requires: cactuar
needle barrage may be taken multiple times, each time needle barrage is taken its effects are applied seperately, and these effects stack with each other. each time needle barrage is taken increase the total number of needles from needle shot by +x, with x being the number of times needle barrage is taken(ex: taken once, 1 instance of +1 needle, taken twice, 2 instances of +2 needles or +4 total, taken thrice, 3 instances of +3 needles or +9 total, etc)

high speed acupuncture
requires: cactuar, needle barrage
you can fire your needle shot at an ally to remove a status effect on them, the kinds of status effects you can remove depends on how many needles you hit them with, consult the chart below, only one status can be removed at a time. targets of highspeed acupuncture take no damage from the needles
	needles:effect
	      2:shaken
	      5:fatigue
	      8:sickened
	     12:dazed
	     16:diseased
	     21:staggered
	     26:exhausted
	     32:cursed
	     38:frightened
	     45:nauseated
	     52:poisoned
	     60:blinded
	     68:deafened
	     77:paralyzed
	     86:stunned
	     96:unconcious
	    106:dying(bleeding out)

1000 needles
requires: cactuar, needle barrage x5
once per day the cactuar may fire off 1000 needles as a full round action, these 1000 needles are evenly distributed between all possible targets within 30 ft(both ally and enemy, dead and alive, illusional and real), each needle only does 1 damage but bypasses damage reduction, a single ranged attack roll is made and the result is compared to the touch AC of all targets to determine if they are hit by their associated needles, targets behind cover are hit by fewer needles than those not(30% miss chance results in 30% of their needles hitting the cover etc). finally firing off 1000 needles is no simple task and the cactuar must make an acrobatics check DC20 after doing so or fall prone

1000 needles(mythic)
requires: 1000 needles
you may focus the 1000 needles onto only enemy targets in range

photosynthetic
requires: cactuar
you rapidly regenerate while in direct sunlight, you gain fast healing 3 +2 for each size catagory you are above small. this stacks with fast healing from other sources

cactrot rapido
requires: cactuar, bab 1+
you are the essence of speed, you gain +10ft move and +6 intiative, gain an additional +90 ft move when going through sand. additionally, other increases to move provide +x additional move in sand, where x is twice the normal bonus to move it provides

sabotender
requires: cactuar
you move up to medium size and double the total number of needles you fire from needle abilities

jumbo
requires cactuar, sabotender, 8+ hit dice 
you move up to the large size catagory, gain +3 hp per hit die, and grow a magnificent moustache that provides +8 on all chr based skill checks, additionally the total number of needles you fire from needle abilities is multiplied by 4 instead of 2

gigantuar
requires: cactuar, sabotender, jumbo, 16+ hit dice
you move up to huge size catagory, gain an additional +5 hp per hit die, you gain a slam attack, +5 ft move, and you gain fast healing 3, additionally the total number of needles you fire from needle abilities is multiplied by 8 instead of 4

favored class bonuses
paladin		+1/4 uses of smite per day
monk		+1 ft move
ninja		+1/4 ninja trick known
cleric		+1/2 caster level for any spell associated with the sun domain
barbarian	+1/4 morale bonuses in rage when fighting multiple enemies alone
rougue		+1/4 dodge bonus to AC
bard		+1 bardic performance rounds per day
skald		+1 to any check to get someone to attack you
ranger		+1/6 favored enemy bonus


tonberry
standard(con+2 int+2 chr-2)
small(0)
slow(-1)
rancor(8)
when a tonberry takes damage, they gain rancor points equal to the damage incurred. at the start of their turn a tonberry may spend a rancor point to recover half the damage they took since their previous turn however doing so prevents them from acting except for taking a 5 ft step. rancor points may not be spent to recover from damage if the tonberry is unconcious, stunned, or otherwise helpless. rancor points are only ever lost if the tonberry expends them. a tonberry can have a max number of rancor points equal to twice her max hp
doink!(8)
when making a melee attack, the tonberry may expend rancor points as a swift action to increase the damage by 1 per 2 rancor points spent, this bonus damage is multiplied on a critical hit. while the tonberry chooses how much rancor to spend on doink, she may not spend more than twice her total hit dice with a given use

total: 15

racial traits

strong tail
your tail has more developed muscles which gives you better control in the water, you gain +2 to swim checks

go for a stroll
you are adapted to seeing things with only a lantern, as long as you do not move faster than 5 ft per turn, you are treated as having low light vision for 30 ft

racial feats

magical hatred
requires: tonberry, ability to cast 1st level spells
you may spend rancor points to increase the damage done by spells, every 5 rancor points increases the damage per die by +1. the tonberry may not spend more than 2 rancor per caster level on a given spell

suppressed hatred
requires: tonberry, magical hatred, ability to cast 3rd level spells
if the tonberry ever finds himself silenced, bound, or otherwise afflicted in a way that would prevent him from casting, he may expend rancor points to cast at reduced effectiveness. the tonberry must spend rancor equal to the spell level of the spell they wish to cast, and their effective caster level is reduced buy an equal amount(to a min of 1). this does not allow the tonberry to cast spells she does not know or would otherwise not have access to

rancorous magic
requires: tonberry, ability to cast 1st lvl spells
you may spend rancor to boost your magical ability in various ways. you may gain a +2 bonus to concentration checks per rancor point spent. you may boost your effective caster level on a spell by 1 per 2 rancor points spent. you may reduce a spells effective level by 1 per 50 rancor spent. these bonus types are not cumulative with each other but you may spend rancor in multiple bonuses on a single spell. the amount of rancor you can spend to boost your concentration check is limited to your caster level. the amount of rancor you can spend to boost your effective caster level is limited to double your total hit dice. 

everyone's grudge
requires: tonberry
you may make a ranged attack as a full round action, if successful you expend all your rancor points to deal 2 damage per rancor point consumed

doink!!
requires: tonberry, 5+ hit dice
drecrease the cost of doink to be 1 rancor point per 1 damage. the limit of how many rancor points may be spent on doink at once remains unchanged

eternal rancor
requires: tonberry, 7+ hit dice
some tonberries have no limit to their hatred, tonberries with this feat have no upper limit on how much rancor they can have

tonberry king(mythic)
requires: tonberry, tonberry king prestige lv 5+
you are a true master of hatred, the total range you may gain empathetic rancor is multiplied by 10. additionally, you may spend 1000 rancor as a full round action to instantly kill 1 target within 30 ft, setting their current hp to a value equal to negative their max hp, this effect has no save and cannot miss

Granular Rancour
Requires: everyone's rancor class feature
you may spend any amount of rancour on everyone's rancour ability, the damage remains the amount of rancour spent squared



favored class bonuses
summoner	+1/3 evolution points
magus		+1/2 to confirm critical hits
eldritch knight	+1/2 to confirm critical hits
sorcerer	+1/6 damage per die on spells
wizard		+1 DC of spells
ninja		+1 DC of poisons
arcanist	+1/2 arcane exploit known
cleric		+1/3 uses of channel energy per day
rougue		+1/3 1d6 sneak attack damage
fighter		+1/2 combat feat


new sorceror bloodlines

water blooded
skill: survival

bonus spells: touch of idiocy(3rd) absurdity(5th) agonizing rebuke(7th) water clear focus(9th) blaze of glory(11th) glibness(13th) insanity(15th) subjective reality(17th) spotinaity(19th)

bonus feats: photosynthetic, quicken spell, fleet, improved initiative, self sufficient, 

bloodline arcana:your thin watery blood is unusual, but it lets you soak up ambient magic. when you or someone within 30 ft casts a spell or uses a spell like ability, you gain a magic fragment stack, up to a max of twice your caster level. you can cast a spell without expending a spell slot by expending 2 magic fragment stacks per spell level

bloodline powers
	
	fast cast(1st) once per round as a free action you can increase the speed at which a spell casts by spending 1 magic fragment stack per spell level. this reduces the cast time by 1 step and stacks with other similar effects such as quicken spell

	oblivious courage(3rd) you dont always understand the danger you're in, but sometimes this works to your advantage, you are perminently under the effect of the absurdity spell. at 5th level you gain a +2 bonus to save vs fear effects. at 12th level the absurdity effect extends to all fear effects

	efficient absorption(9th) you can now absorb magic better, whenever you would gain a magic fragment stack, you gain a number of stacks equal to the spell level

	desert mage(15th) your watery blood grants you unexpected power in the desert, while you stand on or are submerged in sand, you gain a +1 to caster level, survival checks, concentration checks, initiative, and spellcraft checks. this bonus increases by +1 each level after 15th(+6 at 20th)

	magic sponge(20th) when you are targeted with a spell, or are in the aoe of a spell's effect, you may expend a magic fragment stack as an immediate action to soak up and absorb the entire spell, this completely negates the effect of the spell and any metamagic or similar effects the spell would cause and you gain magic fragment stacks equal to the adjusted spell level




rancor blooded
skill:knowledge(history)

bonus spells: vengeful comets(3rd) bestow curse(5th) howling agony(7th) retribution(9th) curse, major(11th) cruel jaunt(13th) blasphemy(15th) disintegrate(17th) time stop(19th)

bonus feats: rancorous magic, heighten spell, empower spell, intensify spell, endurance, die hard, toughness, 

bloodline arcana:
the unending hatred in your blood fuels your magic in strange ways, spells you cast with the curse or pain descriptors increase their save DC by half your caster level(min+1). whenever you deal non-lethal damage, the target must make a fort save, DC equal to the damage dealt or suffer 1/4 as much lethal damage

bloodline powers

	intensify pain(1st) as a swift action you may add the pain descriptor to a spell you're casting that deals damage, however the damage from the spell becomes non-lethal

	painful curse(3rd) whenever a target fails a save against one of your spells with the curse descriptor, they take non-lethal damage equal to the level of the spell

	aim for where it hurts(9th) when you hurt someone, they feel it. whenever you deal lethal damage, you deal half as much non-lethal damage

	screw this guy in particular(15th) your magic layers itself to focus down your enemies, enemies damaged by your spells gain a stack of impending doom, stacks of impending doom last 3 rounds, when you cast a damaging spell against a target with impending doom stacks, the spell gains +1 damage per die for each impending doom stack

	kill thru time(20th) you gain time stop as a spell like ability, usable a number of times per day equal to 3 + your charisma modifier, you may expend a use of this ability during time stop as a swift action to extend the duration of time stop by another use. additionally, while under the effects of time stop, you can cast spells on other targets as if you were not time stopped, however the effect gets frozen in time before hitting its target so any spells cast during time stop on others take effect at the end of time stop. 